Heroes don't get any bigger.
Ant-Man is a science fiction, action, adventure film directed by Peyton Reed.
Armed with the astonishing ability to shrink in scale but increase in strength, master thief Scott Lang must embrace his inner-hero and help
his mentor, Doctor Hank Pym, protect the secret behind his spectacular Ant-Man suit from a new generation of towering threats.
Against seemingly insurmountable obstacles, Pym and Lang must
plan and pull off a heist that will save the world.
Scott Lang / Ant-Man, played by Paul Rudd.
Dr. Hank Pym, played by Michael Douglas.
Hope van Dyne, played by Evangeline Lilly.
Darren Cross / Yellowjacket, played by Corey Stoll.
Paxton, played by Bobby Cannavale.
Sam Wilson / Falcon, played by Anthony Mackie.
Ant-Man is a 2015 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics
characters of the same name: Scott Lang and Hank Pym.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures, it is the 12th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Peyton Reed from a screenplay by the writing teams
of Edgar Wright & Joe Cornish and Adam McKay & Paul Rudd.
It stars Rudd as Scott Lang / Ant-Man alongside Evangeline Lilly, Corey Stoll, Bobby Cannavale, Michael Peña, Tip "T.I." Harris,
Anthony Mackie, Wood Harris, Judy Greer, Abby Ryder Fortson, David Dastmalchian, and Michael Douglas as Hank Pym.
In the film, Lang must help defend Pym's Ant-Man shrinking
technology and plot a heist with worldwide ramifications.
Development of Ant-Man began in April 2006 with the hiring of
Wright to direct and co-write with Cornish.
By April 2011, Wright and Cornish had completed three drafts of the script
and Wright shot test footage for the film in July 2012.
Pre-production began in October 2013 after being put on hold
so that Wright could complete The World's End.
Casting began in December 2013, with the hiring of Rudd to play Lang.
In May 2014, Wright left the project citing creative differences, though he
still received screenplay and story credits with Cornish.
The following month, Reed was brought in to replace Wright, while
McKay was hired to contribute to the script with Rudd.
Filming took place between August and December 2014
in San Francisco and Metro Atlanta.
Ant-Man held its world premiere at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 29, 2015, and
was released in the United States on July 17, as the final film in Phase Two of the MCU.
It grossed more than $519 million worldwide and received positive reviews from critics, who generally welcomed the film's smaller
stakes than other MCU films, as well as its cast (particularly Rudd, Peña, Lilly, and Douglas), humor, and visual effects.
Two sequels have been released: Ant-Man and the Wasp (2018)
and Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania (2023).
The film explores themes of superhero, ant, master
thief, shrinking, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.